<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Donald Jenkins is a writer and photographer</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Donald Jenkins is a writer and photographer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 13:02:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Policymakr</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/introducing-policymakr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 10:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/introducing-policymakr/</guid>
      <description>A quick introduction to Policymakr, the new start-up I&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;ve been planning since the dramatic events of 2016, and which I&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to launch. And a little question-and-answer session, as an added bonus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test article: we need to see what these articles look like on a screen</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/test-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 11:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/test-article/</guid>
      <description>I wish all who read this a very Happy New Year: I am certain I am not the only one hoping that this new decade will mark a new beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I couldn&#39;t do without in 2011</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/stuff-i-couldnt-do-without-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 14:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/stuff-i-couldnt-do-without-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>My regular annual list of material possessions with which I cannot dispense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A better new decade?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/a-better-new-decade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 15:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/a-better-new-decade/</guid>
      <description>I wish all who read this a very Happy New Year: I am certain I am not the only one hoping that this new decade will mark a new beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backing up a Mac to Amazon S3 with Arq: the easiest, safest and most accurate solution</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/backing-up-a-mac-to-amazon-s3-with-arq-the-easiest-safest-and-most-accurate-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 05:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/backing-up-a-mac-to-amazon-s3-with-arq-the-easiest-safest-and-most-accurate-solution/</guid>
      <description>Mac is among the most difficult systems to backup and restore correctly: Macs have peculiarities; resource forks and packages, for example, are unique to the Mac, and not every service handles them well. My experience of the more popular commercial backup services has not been good: they&amp;rsquo;re unreliable, slow and raise privacy and data safety concerns. Using Amazon S3, in combination with a robust yet simple backup tool provided by small startup Arq, which I&amp;rsquo;ve just discovered, provides a much more reliable alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/stuff-i-couldnt-live-without-in-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 16:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/stuff-i-couldnt-live-without-in-2010/</guid>
      <description>Taking inspiration from Michael Arrington and Kevin Rose (I didn’t think Kevin Rose would ever be a source of inspiration, but maybe I’m just feeling lazy), I’ve succumbed to the trend. Here’s the list of stuff I couldn’t possibly do without. It’s much shorter than theirs, and has all the right, cool stuff. If I’m still around, I’ll update it in 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A plea in support of Mr Obama&#39;s perfectible health-care bill</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/a-plea-in-support-of-mr-obamas-perfectible-health-care-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 08:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/a-plea-in-support-of-mr-obamas-perfectible-health-care-bill/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in no doubt that America needs universal health care for the same reasons that Europe needed it in 1945: it&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s morally unacceptable, in a rich society, that anyone should be denied it for financial reasons. The bill presently before Congress is clearly perfectible, but in reality, arguments against it are but thinly-veiled pretexts barely concealing the selfishness and economic ignorance underlying Mr Obama&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s opponents on this issue..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reorganising this blog</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/stuff-i-couldnt-live-without-in-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 01:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/stuff-i-couldnt-live-without-in-2010/</guid>
      <description>The time has come to consolidate all the posts I’ve written since 2005 in a variety of guises, in one language and one site. The language, of course, had to be English and the site had to be donaldjenkins.com. I did toy for a while with the idea of running a bilingual blog. But the SEO implications of this were unclear and I thought it might be overkill. So I translated all the old blog posts, which hadn’t been available online for nearly two years, and uploaded them, for the first time, to this site. They have occasionally been made more concise, and comments (which were in French anyway) haven’t been preserved. You can browse through them by visiting the archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn-of-the-decade tribulations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/turn-of-the-decade-tribulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/turn-of-the-decade-tribulations/</guid>
      <description>My difficult start to a new decade, and the tribulations of the French healthcare system, which is still probably the world&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s best. Competent care is available round-the-clock in Paris, and rich and poor and treated exactly equally, which is how should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A time to gather stones together</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/a-time-to-gather-stones-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 23:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/a-time-to-gather-stones-together/</guid>
      <description>A short post written at a challenging time. Yet one of the many the beautiful things about hardship, when it strikes, is that spiritual comfort is always there when one needs it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I have finally decided to blog in my own name</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/why-i-have-finally-decided-to-blog-in-my-own-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 16:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/why-i-have-finally-decided-to-blog-in-my-own-name/</guid>
      <description>With the change in my lifestyle, interests and job that occurred last year, and also the decision to switch to English after three years of blogging in French, the time has come to draw the process to a logical conclusion and make donaldjenkins.com my only home on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yvonne, princesse de Bourgogne: Gerard Mortier shuts his bolt pretty triumphantly</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/yvonne-princesse-de-bourgogne-gerard-mortier-shuts-his-bolt-pretty-triumphantly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2009 22:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/yvonne-princesse-de-bourgogne-gerard-mortier-shuts-his-bolt-pretty-triumphantly/</guid>
      <description>Over the past four years, Gerard Mortier has presided over a quiet revolution in style, matched by a major shift in the audience of that venerable Parisian institution. He initially got the backs up the stuffy Parisians who traditionally make up the institution’s audience, in blissful ignorance of the true artistic merits of what they have been watching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An amazing mixture of Roland Petit, the Corps de Ballet and Proust</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/an-amazing-mixture-of-roland-petit-the-corps-de-ballet-and-proust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2007 12:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/an-amazing-mixture-of-roland-petit-the-corps-de-ballet-and-proust/</guid>
      <description>A review of RolandPetit&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s impressive ballet &lt;em&gt;Proust ou les intermittences du coeur&lt;/em&gt; : « Les enfers de Monsieur de Charlus ».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should France change her national anthem?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/should-france-change-her-national-anthem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2007 03:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/should-france-change-her-national-anthem/</guid>
      <description>A modest, and rather frivolous, contribution to the debate that sometimes recurs about the words of France&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s national anthem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have been know to enjoy Rosenkavalier sometimes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/i-have-been-known-to-enjoy-rosenkavalier-sometimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2007 11:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/i-have-been-known-to-enjoy-rosenkavalier-sometimes/</guid>
      <description>I’m always uncomfortable with Strauss. I find him impossible to fathom, which makes me deeply unpopular in certain circles. Salome, which I went to see a few months ago, was a terribly difficult experience. Many of my friends found it wonderful. So I wasn’t feeling my best when I set off with a friend to the Opera Bastille to see Rosenkavalier, whose first performance I had missed in December</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Word was made flesh. Got that?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/and-the-word-was-made-flesh-got-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 11:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/and-the-word-was-made-flesh-got-that/</guid>
      <description>Quite simply put, the most important words ever written: a recollection for Christmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idomeneo: a lyrical turning point</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/idomeneo-a-lyrical-turning-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2006 18:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/idomeneo-a-lyrical-turning-point/</guid>
      <description>Idomeneo is a major turning-point, not just in Mozart’s music, but in the history of opera. Albert Einstein said of Idomeneo that it was one of those works that even a genius of the highest rank like Mozart could only write once in his life. And it’s unquestionably radically different from anything Mozart composed before or afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benjamin Millepied takes Paris by storm</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/benjamin-millepied-takes-paris-by-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2006 16:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/benjamin-millepied-takes-paris-by-storm/</guid>
      <description>A review of Benjamin Millepied&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s ballet &lt;em&gt;Amoveo&lt;/em&gt;, which was attended by a huge concourse of people from Paris and New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The French themselves don&amp;#8217;t realise how beautifully French Les Troyens is</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-french-themselves-dont-realise-how-beautifully-french-les-troyens-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 17:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-french-themselves-dont-realise-how-beautifully-french-les-troyens-is/</guid>
      <description>A quick review of &lt;em&gt;Les Troyens&lt;/em&gt;, arguably France&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s most beautiful opera, and rather inexplicably quite misunderstood. Gerard Mortier, director of the Paris Opera, has rightly gone against this trend by making it the highlight of the year&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chopin: such appropriate music for a ballet</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/chopin-such-appropriate-music-for-a-ballet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2006 09:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/chopin-such-appropriate-music-for-a-ballet/</guid>
      <description>A review of &lt;em&gt;La Dame aux camellias&lt;/em&gt; directed by Neumaier, Americas most European choreographer. A truly splendid production with the world’s best ballet company, sublime music, Jürgen Rose’s breathtakingly beautiful costumes. The music was superb, but Chopin was a frequent source of inspiration for choreographers, so Neumeier is merely following established precedent here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheap Monday or how to be thin, poor and fashionable</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/cheap-monday-or-how-to-be-thin-poor-and-fashionable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2006 23:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/cheap-monday-or-how-to-be-thin-poor-and-fashionable/</guid>
      <description>One sometimes feels that a famous saying by the Duchess of Windsor ought to be qualified, or even applied in reverse: nowadays, if you want to be fashionable, you can never be too thin (that bit hasn’t changed), or too poor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Dame aux Camélias: crusty old fogeys, jumping for joy</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/la-dame-aux-camelias-crusty-old-fogeys-jumping-for-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 00:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/la-dame-aux-camelias-crusty-old-fogeys-jumping-for-joy/</guid>
      <description>A review of Neumeier&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;La Dame aux camellias&lt;/em&gt;. I wonder why it took so long for this wonderful ballet piece, created in 1978, to be included in the Opera’s &lt;em&gt;répertoire&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capote and the death penalty: turning the clock back to 1967</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/capote-and-the-death-penalty-turning-the-clock-back-to-1967/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2006 22:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/capote-and-the-death-penalty-turning-the-clock-back-to-1967/</guid>
      <description>A review of the film about Truman, Capote, in which one deliberately veers somewhat off-topic, focusing more on the curious way in which he approached the death penalty on the occasion of his trip to Kansas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would the Social Register types in New York hate Haneke too?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/would-the-social-register-types-in-new-york-hate-haneke-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2006 20:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/would-the-social-register-types-in-new-york-hate-haneke-too/</guid>
      <description>Don Giovanni is Mozart’s most avantgardist opera: it was a major benchmark for nineteenth-century composers. Yet Haneke who directed this production, was booed copiously at Friday’s first performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abomination in Iran</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/aabomination-in-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 21:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/aabomination-in-iran/</guid>
      <description>My first real blog post was about an abomination. I have not been able to get the devastating news about the mollah regime in power in Iran&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;s hanging of two innocent teenagers, for the sole reason that they were in a relationship. That a country that used to be the most western-friendly, modern and open society in the region to fallen into the hands of these bloodthirsty, barbarian thugs is simply inexplicable by rational means</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;ve decided to keep a blog</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/why-ive-decided-to-keep-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2005 10:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/why-ive-decided-to-keep-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>In this initial post, written at Saint Tropez, one explains why one has succumbed the trend for keeping a blog, all the while hoping I would not prove a passing fad. Time will tell.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
